# **Nick Bolles**

10210 Rustling Birch Rd. Apt 221 Verona, WI 53593 (715) 781-5549 me@NickBolles.com www.NickBolles.com

### **About Me**

Hello, I'm Nick. I love development, business philosophy, and discovering new technologies. I have experience with a wide array of technologies, with a passion for web development and emerging technologies. I take an iterative approach to development by emphasizing clean code, unit testing, devops, open source and standards-based technology. I also have a business focused mindset, which enables me to consider how technology impacts business outcomes as well as how business needs drive technology advances. I enjoy brainstorming ways to solve business challenges with technology solutions to achieve efficient, effective, and low cost results.

# Skills

- Strong understanding of business and how technology can influence day-to-day business operations
- Strong knowledge of the software development process and how aspects affect business outcomes
- Excellent development skills including: Typescript, Angular (1.x and 2+), React, Vue, SASS, NodeJS, Feathersjs, MongoDB, GraphQL, ASP.net, Database design, and more
- Experience with software development tools and methods such as Git, SVN, UML, Balsamiq, Docker, Gitlab, Gitlab CI/CD, NPM, Gulp, Webpack, Cordova, Agile, and Scrum

# **Experience**

## Epic, Verona WI - Software Developer

June 2017 - Present

- Full stack developer responsible for project planning, design, development, and testing
- Application point person for several areas, such as performance testing and training tools
- Learn to formulate viable solutions to complex challenges that large software companies struggle with
- Assisted in establishing new area of ownership for complex and company-wide integrated functionality
- Designed and developed batch edit tool to save thousands of hours a year across the healthcare industry
  - Effectively organize designs and project timeline to accommodate for challenges encountered
  - Established robust guardrails & error management processes to further reduce management time

### Epic, Verona WI - Software Developer Intern

May 2016 - August 2016

- Designed and developed a mobile IOS app in Swift
- Effectively communicated with end users and mentors to incorporate feedback into design
- Implemented a working prototype and presented to peers and division leaders

#### Geodigital, Mendota Heights, MN - Software Developer Intern

May 2014 - January 2016

- Completed a self driven project to develop a dynamic documentation system for web services
- Only summer intern to secure a position beyond the scheduled internship end date of August 2014

#### Education

#### **University of Wisconsin - Whitewater**

September 2013 - May 2017

- Bachelor of Business Administration in Information Technology Emphasis on Business Analysis
- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science